Borys Hlynskyi

Software Engineer

bglinskii6@gmail.com+380681485935

Ternopil, UkraineLinkedin Profile Link, Github

Software Engineer with over 3 years of experience specializing in frontend development. Proficient in creating static websites and single-page applications utilizing a variety of technologies, including WordPress and React/Vue. Also familiar with JS backend tech like Node.js / Express.js / MongoDB.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer 04/2023 - 10/2024

Exadel

Ternopil, Ukraine

- Developing and maintaining user interface components and pages for the content team to use, ensuring
 ease of use and consistency.
- Crafting reusable components and styles to streamline development and ensure scalability across projects.
- Maintaining the project's code architecture, continuously suggesting and implementing new approaches to improve structure, efficiency, and maintainability
- Ensuring full accessibility compliance across all components and pages, adhering to best practices and web standards.
- Optimizing website performance through strategic enhancements, reducing load times and improving overall user experience. This helped to get a 90+ lighthouse score.
- Developing and supporting a standalone full-stack project, integrated seamlessly into the main site.
- Collaborating with cross-functional teams, including conducting code reviews, providing accurate task estimations, and working closely with QA, Business Analysts, and designers to meet project goals.

Technologies: JavaScript, WebComponents, SCSS, Twig, React, Tailwind, AntDesign, Node & Express, Mongoose, Vite.

Junior Software Engineer

10/2021 - 03/2024

Exadel

Ternopil, Ukraine

- Developing new features to enhance functionality and improve user experience across the website.
- Implementing redesigns of landing pages, ensuring modern design principles and best practices are followed.
- Actively participating in requirements definition, collaborating with stakeholders to ensure clear and actionable goals for development.
- Performing manual testing and bug fixing to maintain high-quality standards and ensure smooth functionality.
- Code reviews.
- Identifying and fixing bugs, ensuring the stability and reliability of the project..

- Performing research and investigation to identify optimal solutions and approaches for new implementations.
- Refactoring and updating legacy components, improving code readability, performance, and alignment with modern standards

Technologies: JavaScript, TypeScript, WebComponents, 11ty, Nunjucks, LESS, Vue 2, VueX, Tailwind

EDUCATION

Masters in Software EngineeringWest Ukrainian National University
09/2022 - 12/2023

Bachelors in Software EngineeringWest Ukrainian National University
09/2018 - 06/2022